Guide to the John E. Fleming Papers, 1962-2013 RL.11014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Museum Leadership, 1981-2014
  - National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, 1996-2004; 7
    - The Links Legacy signature project at NURFC, undated (Box 15)
    - Freedom's Flame (newsletter), 1999-2001 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous clippings and documents, 2000-2003 (Box 15)
    - Programs, events, publicity, 1998-2004 (Box 15)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 15)
    - Cincinnati and the Underground Railroad research and notes, 1999 and undated (Box 15)
    - Underground Railroad research and notes, 1990s-2000 (Box 15)
  - Cincinnati Museum Center, 1996-2004; 8
    Various materials from Fleming's tenure as Vice President of Museums at the Cincinnati Museum Center, 2001-2007. Includes assorted documents from several CMC museums, exhibits, and programs, as well as administrative files, strategic planning, and Fleming's personnel materials.
    - Personnel file, 2001-2007 (Box 15)
    - ID card, other memorabilia, undated (Box 15)
    - Contract work, 2008 (Box 15)
    - Board of Trustees, 2005-2011 (Box 15)
    - African American advisory board, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Cincinnati history museum, 2004 (Box 15)
    - Grants, fundraising, planning, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Annual reports, 2003-2009 (Box 15)
    - Events, undated (Box 15)
    - Press coverage, clippings, undated (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 2000s (Box 15)
    - Collections management, 2006-2007 (Box 15)
    - Youth programs, undated (Box 15)
    - Second Life research, undated (Box 15)
    - News from Our Past lecture series, 2004-2005 (Box 15)
    - Integrated education programs budgets, 2004 (Box 15)
    - Integrated education program grant materials and overviews, 2004 (Box 15)
    - Holiday events and programs, 2005 (Box 15)
    - John Ruthven exhibit, 2004-2005 (Box 15)
    - Strategic planning, undated (Box 15)
    - New ventures committee, undated (Box 15)
    - Freedom's Sisters exhibit, undated (Box 15)
    - Civil Unrest in Cincinnati exhibit, 2001 (Box 15)
    - "Target America: Opening Eyes to the Damage Drugs Cause", undated (Box 15)
    - UC Public History Practicum, "West End/Mallory Family" exhibit design, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Race exhibit, 2007-2008 (Box 15)
    - Space/science exhibit, undated (Box 15)
    - First We Make America exhibit, 2011-2012 (Box 15)
  - National Museum of African American History and Culture, 2002-2009; 9
    Materials from Fleming's service on the Presidential Commission of the National Museum of African American History and Culture, including site visits, meeting notes, reports, and exhibit proposals.
    - African American institutional study final report, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Appointment affidavit, 2003 Mar. 20 (Box 16)
    - Briefing book: second meeting, 2002 Sept. 24-25 (Box 16)
    - Clippings, press releases, and articles, undated (Box 16)
    - Commission materials, 2003 Mar. (Box 16)
    - Commission meeting, 2003 Mar. 23-26 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 16)
    - Documents and correspondence re: commission meeting, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Final report: planning and organizing for a private sector fundraising campaign, 2003 Mar. 15 (Box 16)
    - Final report to the president and to the congress, 3rd draft, 2003 Apr. 2 (Box 16)
    - Final site report, 2003 Sept. (Box 16)
    - Fourth commission meeting, 2003 Mar. 24-25 (Box 16)
    - Interim Report to the President and the Congress, 2003 Jan. (Box 16)
    - National Survey of African American Museums, 2003 Mar. 17 (Box 16)
    - Plan for Action: Presidential Commission, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Preferred site analysis report, 2002 Dec. 3 (Box 16)
    - Site briefing book, 2002 Sept. 25 (Box 16)
    - Jump, Jazz, and Jive: The Apollo Theater and American Entertainment narrative script, 2009 Apr. (Box 16)
    - The Time has Come: Report to the President and to the Congress, 2003 Apr. 2 (Box 16)
    - Building program, existing facility survey, site analysis, master plan, undated (Box 39)
  - America I Am Exhibit, 2007-2011; 14
    Contains extensive notes, correspondence, and internal documentation from the planning process for Tavis Smiley's America I Am: African American Imprint on America, a 12,000 square foot traveling exhibition; Fleming served as Executive Producer of the project. The exhibit opened in Philadelphia in 2009 and toured throughout the country until 2011.
    - Correspondence and notes, 2007-2009; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Smiley Group, 2007-2008 (Box 24)
    - Advisory Panel, 2007 (Box 24)
    - Exhibit consultants/content team, 2007-2009 (Box 24)
    - Contracts, 2007-2009 (Box 24)
    - Salary, 2007-2009 (Box 24)
    - Exhibit team meetings, 2007 Jun.-2008 Aug.; 10 folders (Box 24)
    - NAACP convention, 2008 July (Box 24)
    - Exhibit revisions, 2008 Aug. (Box 24)
    - Timeline/exhibit preparations, 2008-2009 (Box 24)
    - Meetings/notes, general, 2007-2009 (Box 24)
    - Meetings/notes: Slavery scholars, 2007-2008 (Box 24)
    - Meetings/notes: Race, Culture, and Society scholars, 2007-2008 (Box 24)
    - Meetings/notes: Sports scholars, 2007-2008 (Box 24)
    - Meetings/notes: Religion scholars, 2007-2008 (Box 24)
    - Meetings/notes: Music scholars, 2007-2008 (Box 24)
    - Exhibit loan agreements, 2007-2009 (Box 24)
    - Artifacts/loans: Artifact searches, 2008; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Artifacts/loans: Collections search, 2008 (Box 24)
    - Artifacts/loans: MLK Estate, 2008 (Box 24)
    - Artifacts/loans: Carol Mundy Collection, 2008 (Box 24)
    - Artifacts/loans: Requests, contacts, 2008 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: Early ideas, notes, 2007 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: Slave trade, 2008 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: National Constitution Center, 2009 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: Atlanta Civic Center, 2009 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: Cincinnati Museum Center, 2009-2010 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: Washington DC, 2010-2011 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: St. Louis, 2011 (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: Los Angeles, 2010 and undated (Box 25)
    - Artifacts/loans: Lenders, labels and drafts, 2008 and undated (Box 25)
    - Floor plans/case plans and designs, 2009 and undated; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Preliminary label list, undated (Box 25)
    - Titles and messages (drafts), 2008 (Box 25)
    - Exhibit labels (drafts), undated (Box 25)
    - Labels: reviewer comments, 2008 Sept. (Box 25)
    - Quilt exhibit, undated (Box 25)
    - Educational component, 2008 and undated (Box 25)
    - Mobile tour narrative, 2008 (Box 25)
    - Press packets, 2008-2009 (Box 26)
    - Press/publicity, 2009-2010 (Box 26)
    - Exhibit bills, 2009-2010 (Box 26)
    - Smithsonian partnership, 2007 (Box 26)
    - New York Historical Society, 2007-2008 (Box 26)
    - Exhibit openings receipts/reimbursements, 2009 (Box 26)
    - Travel reimbursements, 2007-2009; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Grand opening: National Constitution Center, 2009 (Box 26)
    - Exhibit opening and press, Atlanta, 2009 (Box 26)
    - Exhibit opening, Los Angeles, 2009 (Box 26)
    - Exhibit opening, Cincinnati, 2010 (Box 26)
    - Exhibit opening, Washington DC, 2011 (Box 26)
    - Floor plans, 2008 November 12 (Box 39)
  - International African American Museum, 2007-2013; 18
    Includes materials from the planning and design of the International African American Museum in Charleston, SC, scheduled to open in 2017. Fleming served as advisor and part-time director.
    - Beginnings of IAAM records, 2003-2007 (Box 31)
    - Articles of incorporation and by-laws, 2005 (Box 31)
    - Organization of IAAM, 2007 June (Box 31)
    - Sample policies and procedures for IAAM, 2010 (Box 31)
    - Fleming independent contractor agreements, 2009-2011 (Box 31)
    - Joint Collections Policy, 2005 (Box 31)
    - Board retreat, 2009 August 24 (Box 31)
    - Concept design, 2010 August (Box 31)
    - Fly-Through Fundraising Video, 2010 (Box 31)
    - Project notes: architecture, 2009 (Box 31)
    - IAAM Interpretave framework, 2010 February (Box 31)
    - Revisioning IAAM, undated (Box 31)
    - Strategic plans, 2013 (Box 31)
    - IAAM Case statement and fundraising plan, 2010 (Box 31)
    - Project budget, 2009-2011 (Box 31)
    - Board and committee meetings, 2009 November-December (Box 31)
    - Surveys/interviews, 2009 (Box 31)
    - Content consultants, 2009 (Box 31)
    - Content narrative drafts, undated (Box 31)
    - Concept design booklets, 2012 May (Box 31)
    - Final report for conceptual design phase, 2011 August (Box 31)
    - Budget documents, reports and notes, 2011 (Box 31)
    - HUD grants, 2008-2010 (Box 31)
    - Boeing Grant application, 2013 (Box 31)
    - Board meeting notes and documents, 2009-2012 (Box 31)
    - Strategic planning committee meeting, 2012 May 7 (Box 31)
    - Executive committee meeting, 2012 December 13 (Box 31)
    - Meetings with Chairman William Johnson, undated (Box 31)
    - Documents on James Campbell, former board member, undated (Box 31)
    - Preparation for workshop with mayor, 2011 (Box 31)
    - Meeting with Mayor Riley, 2009 (Box 32)
    - DC curators meeting, 2010 December 2-4 (Box 32)
    - Summer/fall curator's meeting, 2010 (Box 32)
    - Meeting with Congressman Clyburn, 2009 July 21 (Box 32)
    - Ralph Applebaum Associates, undated (Box 32)
    - AME Zion Church, 2010 (Box 32)
    - Collaborative partnership with Trident Tech, 2012 (Box 32)
    - Exhibit narrative, 2009 (Box 32)
    - Exhibit designs, 2009-2010 (Box 32)
    - The Palmetto Project, 2011 July (Box 32)
    - Exhibit planning meeting, 2009 September (Box 32)
    - The Museum of the Passage, 2001 January 11-12 (Box 32)
    - African Passage planning proposal, 2011 October 4 (Box 32)
    - First We Make America overview, 2011 October 15 (Box 32)
    - A Dictate of Both Interest and Mercy?, undated (Box 32)
    - I Can Do the Child No Good, 2007 (Box 32)
    - Between the Tracks, undated (Box 32)
    - Civil Rights exhibit, 2012 (Box 32)
    - Robinson Quilt exhibition, 2011 (Box 32)
    - Information on Sullivan Island Pest Houses, undated (Box 32)
    - Board Meeting: Charleston's Arrival Square, undated (Box 32)
    - Workshop: Charleston's Arrival Square, undated (Box 32)
    - Information for New Tour Guides, undated; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - The Fire Every Time, 2012 September 21-22 (Box 32)
    - Capitol Campaign documents, 2010 (Box 32)
    - Website mock-ups, 2012 July 17 (Box 32)
    - Website design review meeting, 2012 September 25 (Box 32)
    - The Urban/Rural gallery, undated (Box 32)
    - Africa Gallery, undated (Box 32)
    - Images for IAAM American, undated (Box 32)
    - National Historica Landmark documents, 2012 (Box 32)
    - NPS Memos of understanding, undated (Box 33)
    - Executive summary: Arrival Sqaure, 2012 September 12 (Box 33)
    - Awareness, Attitudes, and Usage of IAAM, 2009 June 10 (Box 33)
    - City Slicker, 2011 (Box 33)
    - Rollout of IAAM, 2012 (Box 33)
    - Yaschik Foundation proposal, 2012 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and notes, 2008-2012 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous financial documents, 2010-2012 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 2010-2012 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous clippings and documents, undated (Box 33)
    - Planning, floor plans, 2010 June 15 (Box 39)
    - IAAM concept book, 2010 June 22 (Box 39)
    - Concept design, 2010 March (Box 39)
  - Mississippi Civil Rights Museum, 2011-2015; 19
    Materials from Fleming's work with the Mississippi Civil Rights Museum, including project designs, surveys, and grant applications. Fleming was hired by Hilferty and Associates, the design firm responsible for the MCRM. The MCRM's anticipated opening is 2017.
    - Miscellaneous notes and documents, 2011-2012 (Box 34)
    - Team meeting documents, 2012 Feb. 7 (Box 34)
    - Hilferty meeting documents, 2012 Feb. 27-Mar. 2 (Box 34)
    - Hattiesburg community meeting documents and notes, 2012 Feb. (Box 34)
    - Hilferty Inspiration Graphics/Visitor Experience plan sketches/Artifact summary, 2012 (Box 34)
    - Hilferty Preliminary Media Concepts, 2012 Apr. (Box 34)
    - Multimedia Treatments, 2012 Oct. (Box 34)
    - Mississippi Department of Archives and History (MDAH) staff responses, 2012 Dec. 7 (Box 34)
    - Jackson meeting notes and documents, 2013 Jan. 28-Feb. 1 (Box 34)
    - Meeting notes and documents, 2012 Nov.-2013 Mar. (Box 34)
    - Audiovisual treatment outlines, 2012-2013; 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Exhibit development worksheets, 2012-2013; 4 folders (Box 34)
    - Exhibit concepts workshop, 2012 Apr. (Box 34)
    - Schematic Design Phase final report, 2012 Jun. 21 (Box 34)
    - Planning notes and documents, 2011-2013; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Mississippi Bicentennial Plan, 2014-2015 (Box 34)
    - Storyline Matrix drafts, 2012 (Box 34)
    - Interim Progress Reports no. 2-4, 2012-2013; 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Civil Rights timeline drafts, 2012 and undated (Box 34)
    - Progress drawings (oversize), 2012-2013; 4 folders (Box 38)
- Printed Materials and Research, 1965-2011; 5
  Fleming's Printed Materials and Research contain his subject files on various topics, largely related to affirmative action, African American history, and museum operations -- including planning and design of exhibits, educational programs, curation, finances, and leadership. Formats range from printed publications to newspaper clippings. Some materials include Fleming's annotations.
  - AASLH, 2005-2011 (Box 9)
  - Affirmative action, undated (Box 9)
  - African American men, undated (Box 9)
  - African American women, undated (Box 9)
  - American history, undated (Box 9)
  - Arts, music, theater, undated (Box 9)
  - Berea College, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Black power, 2009 (Box 9)
  - Book reviews collected by J. Fleming, 1974-1979 (Box 9)
  - Civil War, 1998-2002 (Box 9)
  - Cultural heritage, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Diversity/multiculturalism, 1987-1999 (Box 9)
  - Finances, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Higher education: diversity/equality/desegregation, 1973-1991 (Box 9)
  - Integration/segregation, 2004-2005 (Box 9)
  - Kentucky: labor/employment, 1971-1975 (Box 9)
  - Museums: African American museums, 1974-2000 (Box 9)
  - Museums: collections/acquisition, ca 2006 (Box 10)
  - Museums: education/outreach, 2000-2004 (Box 10)
  - Museums: exhibitions, undated (Box 10)
  - Museums: management, 1981-1983 (Box 10)
  - Museums: planning, 1983-1997 (Box 10)
  - Museums: site management examples/case studies, 1991; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Museums: visitors/patrons, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Ohio, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Racism/race, 1980-2003 (Box 10)
  - Reconciliation, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Slavery/slave trade, 1975-2009 (Box 10)
- Asa Spaulding Project, 1978-1980; 1
  This series consists largely of Fleming's notes and interview transcripts from his work as a research assistant for Asa Spaulding, who intended to write an autobiography in the early 1980s. Fleming conducted oral history interviews with many of Spaulding's acquaintances and colleagues in support of the project, and also researched Spaulding's personal history. Some audiotapes of interviews are available for research. Transcripts and notes are arranged alphabetically by interviewee.
  - Research, 1979-1980; 1
    - Fleming's notes, etc. (Box 35)
  - Research, 1978-1980; 2
    - Correspondence (Box 35)
  - Research, 1960s-1980s; 3
    - Clippings and research re: Spaulding (Box 35)
  - Bean, Maurice, 1979-11-18; 4
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0001)
  - Berry, John L., 1979-10-12; 5
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0001)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0009)
  - Bouleware, C.E., 1978-06; 6
    - Notes (Box 35)
  - Brennan, Isadora, 1979-04-04; 7
    - Transcript (Box 35)
  - Bryant, R. Kelly, Jr., 1979-03-01; 8
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0002)
  - Burns, William, 1979-06-27; 9
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0003)
  - Butler, E.M., 1979-04-06; 10
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0004)
  - Campbell, J.E., 1979-06; 11
    - Transcript excerpt and notes (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0003)
  - Carterette, Clara, 1979-04-05; 12
    - Notes (Box 35)
  - Clement, W.A., 1979-04-04; 13
    - Transcript (Box 35)
  - Dowdy, Dr. Lewis, 1979-06-25; 14
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0005)
  - Edmunds, Dr. Helen, 1979-04-02; 15
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0007)
  - Green, Paul, 1979-04-02; 16
    - Notes (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0007)
  - Gregg, N.L., 1979-06-25; 17
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0005)
  - Henderson, J.J., 1979-04-02; 18
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0006)
  - Jones, Doctor (Dorsie), 1979-03-01; 19
    - Transcript excerpt (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0002)
  - Kennedy, W.J., Jr., and Meg Kennedy, 1979-03-01; 1979-06-27; 20
    - Transcript excerpt and notes (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0002)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0007)
  - Lynch, Lorenzo, 1979-04-02; 21
    - Notes (Box 35)
  - Mays, Benjamin, 1978-12-18; 22
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0008)
  - Michaux, H.M., 1979-04-02; 23
    - Notes (Box 35)
  - Nichols, Dr. Owen B., 1979-10-11; 24
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0009)
  - Dr. Patterson, circa 1979; 25
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0010)
  - Rollings, Steed, 1979-06-28; 26
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0003)
  - Sansom, James, 1979-06-28; 27
    - Notes (Box 35)
  - Scarborough, Dewey, 1979-06-27; 28
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0003)
  - Spaulding, Dr. Asa T., 1979-01-31; 1979-02-01; 29
    - Transcripts (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0011)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0012)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0013)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0014)
  - Spaulding, John Andrew, 1979-03-29; 30
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0015)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0016)
  - Spears, A.E., 1979-06-22; 31
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0017)
  - Swindell, Edward, 1979-06-27; 32
    - Transcript excerpt (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0005)
  - Dr. Thorn, circa 1979; 33
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0010)
  - Watts, C.D., 1979-04-03; 34
    - Notes (Box 35)
  - White, N.B., 1979-04-04; 35
    - Notes (Box 35)
  - Williams, Dr. Lorraine, 1979-09-26; 36
    - Transcript (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0018)
  - Woods, Dr. Geraldine, 1979-09-19; 37
    - Transcript with edits (Box 35)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 40, Audio-cassette RL11014-CS-0018)
  - Wyche, Henry, 1979-04-05; 38
    - Notes (Box 35)
- Education, 1964-1990; 6
  The Education Series includes files from Fleming's college and graduate work at Berea College and Howard University, as well as his teaching and departmental materials from his work as a professor in Howard University's History Dept. Fleming's dissertation drafts are available in the Writings Series.
  - College and Graduate Work, 3
    - Social psychology, Spring 1964 (Box 10)
    - Independent study: reconstruction of South Carolina, Spring 1965 (Box 10)
    - Political science 213, Spring 1966 (Box 10)
    - History 427, Spring 1966 (Box 10)
    - History 606, Fall 1966 (Box 10)
    - Berea College graduation, 1966 (Box 10)
    - International affairs, Spring 1968 (Box 10)
    - History 335, Fall 1970 (Box 10)
    - African civilizations, Fall 1970 (Box 10)
    - East African history, Spring 1971 (Box 10)
    - History 263, Spring 1971 (Box 10)
    - History 333, Spring 1971 (Box 10)
    - American intellectual, Fall 1971 (Box 10)
    - Negro in the modern world, Fall 1971 (Box 10)
    - Blacks and the American political system, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Africa since 1919, Spring 1972 (Box 11)
    - The negro in urban America, Spring 1972 (Box 11)
    - History 334, Spring 1972 (Box 11)
    - Course notes History 239, Spring 1972 (Box 11)
    - US history 1789-1865, Fall 1972 (Box 11)
    - History 207, Fall 1972 (Box 11)
    - Interdisciplinary history, Fall 1972 (Box 11)
    - Readings in Afro-American history, Fall 1972 (Box 11)
    - Independent study: Marcus Garvey, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Thesis drafts and notes, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Essay and research on W.E.B. DuBois, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Research on George Washington, 1972 (Box 11)
    - United States intellectual history, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
    - History of colonial society, Fall 1973 (Box 11)
    - Transcripts, 1965-1978 (Box 11)
    - Ancient Greek civilization, undated (Box 11)
    - Dissertation notes and research, undated (Box 11)
    - History 262, undated (Box 11)
    - History 327, undated (Box 11)
    - History 328, undated (Box 11)
    - History 428: Book critique, undated (Box 11)
    - History of the Christian church, undated (Box 11)
    - Introduction to historiography and historical method, undated (Box 11)
    - Survey of English history, undated (Box 11)
    - Work for Dr. Rayford Logan, undated (Box 11)
    - Graduate curriculum committee, undated (Box 11)
    - Graduate school documents, undated (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 11)
    - Bibliographies and resources, undated (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous course materials, undated (Box 11)
  - Howard Department of History, 4
    - Oral history course, undated (Box 12)
    - Course readings in American slavery, undated (Box 12)
    - Civil War, recosntruction, and slavery, undated (Box 12)
    - Civil War and reconstruction, 1975 and undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Memphis/Atlanta conference, 1976 Nov. (Box 12)
    - Blacks in Southern Appalachia after Emancipation: A Social History, undated (Box 12)
    - Afro-American history after 1865, undated (Box 12)
    - Record of select activities, undated (Box 12)
    - EEOC proposed guidelines, undated (Box 12)
    - Events, undated (Box 12)
    - Blacks in American politics, undated (Box 12)
    - Slavery in the southern United States, Spring 1978 (Box 12)
    - Memberships, undated (Box 12)
    - Grant proposal: Blacks in southern Appalachia after emancipation, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
    - Rayford Logan, undated (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous research, undated (Box 12)
    - African American history course materials and notes, undated (Box 12)
    - Department newsletters and mailings, 1970s-1990s (Box 12)
- Personal, 1965-2011; 21
  The Personal Series includes an assortment of files, including some of Fleming's job applications as well as various calendars and datebooks, resumes and biographies, clippings about him and his family, and other ephemera that he collected and saved.
  - Clippings re: JEF, 1972-2010 (Box 35)
  - Clippings re: JEF, 1975-2008 (Box 35)
  - Clippings re: family, 1973-2011 (Box 35)
  - Membership/ID cards, 1981-2007 (Box 35)
  - Friends/family obituaries, funerals, 1980s-1990s (Box 35)